Ivy Ledbetter Lee Papers, 1881-2003 (bulk 1915-1946): Finding Aid MC085
Public Policy Papers
Ivy Ledbetter Lee Papers
1881-2003
1915-1946
Public Policy Papers
Lee, Ivy L. (Ivy Ledbetter), 1877-1934.
MC085
159 boxes
1 folder
The Ivy L. Lee Papers consist of personal papers and material from the public relations firm of Ivy Lee and Associates, documenting Ivy Lee's public relations theories and practice. Included are correspondence, diaries, articles, writings, public relations material, newsreels, and photographs reflecting Lee's interest in public relations, transportation (especially railroads), financial markets, and foreign relations, among others. The Papers also contain documents relating to other Lee family members including Reverend James W. Lee (father), Emma Eufaula Lee (mother), Cornelia Bartlett Bigelow Lee (wife), Alice Lee Cudlipp (daughter), James W. Lee II (son), and Ivy L. Lee, Jr. (son).
Biographical / Historical
Ivy L. Lee was born in Cedartown, Georgia on July 16, 1877 of Emma Eufaula Ledbetter Lee and the Reverend Dr. James Wideman Lee, a well known Methodist clergyman in the South. Ivy Lee's childhood was spent in Atlanta, Georgia, except for his senior year in high school, spent in St. Louis, Missouri. He attended Emory College in Atlanta for two years and then transferred to Princeton University, from which he graduated in 1898. While at Princeton, Lee was active on the college newspaper and won the Lynde debate prize.
Lee did post-graduate work at Harvard and Columbia Universities, but due to lack of funds, he entered newspaper work. He was a journalist at the New York American, the New York Times, and the New York World. He preferred to write about business and financial affairs. His first work in public relations came in 1903 as publicity manager for the Citizens' Union. He authored the textbook The Best Administration New York City Ever Had, used in Seth Low's unsuccessful mayoral campaign. Lee then took a press job with the Democratic National Committee.
Lee and George Parker, press agent for the Democratic National Committee, opened the pioneering public relations firm of Parker and Lee in 1905. Parker provided the connections and Lee the creativity in this venture. In an era of muckraking journalism, Lee saw the benefit public relations work could have for big business, believing that if people were presented with all the facts on both sides of an issue, they would not come down so harshly on business interests. Lee saw his role as interpreting the public to the industrialists and the industrialist to the people. To achieve this end, Lee believed in supplying the newspapers with as much information as possible. His "Declaration of Principles," drafted during the anthracite coal strike in the spring of 1906, explained the guiding precepts of his public relations theory. The main points of the Declaration were to guarantee the accuracy of facts and leave to the discretion of the newspaper editor whether an item was worth printing as news. The aim was to provide news, not advertising.
Another opportunity to practice Lee's principles came with work for the Pennsylvania Railroad in 1906. The railroad had a policy of refusing reporters access to all accident sites and refusing to grant interviews. This policy led to reporters' mistrust of the railroad and in turn mistrust on the part of the general public. Lee immediately opened the lines of communication with frequent updates and arranged for reporters to travel to accident sites. In 1908 Lee joined the Pennsylvania Railroad full time, in charge of their publicity bureau.
In 1910 Lee and his young family sailed to Europe, where he arranged to open European offices for the investment firm of Harris, Winthrop, and Company. While in London, Lee delivered a series of lectures at the London School of Economics on railroads. On December 1, 1912 he became executive assistant to the president of the Pennsylvania Railroad. This position gave Lee the opportunity to help influence policy, not just react to incidents at the railroad. Much of Lee's energy was spent in fighting the public clamor to lower freight rates. In 1914 the president of the railroad lent Lee to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to help counter negative press during strikes at the Colorado Fuel and Oil Company mines.
Lee's work for Rockefeller led to the acceptance of a position on the personal advisory staff of John D. Rockefeller, Sr. beginning January 1, 1915. About a year later, he ended his employ with the Rockefellers, determined to open an independent publicity firm (see below). During World War I, Lee served as publicity director and later as Assistant to the Chairman of the American Red Cross.
As the firm prospered, with T. J. Ross taking on more duties as day to day manager during the late 1920s and early 1930s, Lee turned his attention to international concerns. He turned his lifelong interest in Russia into a one-man campaign for recognition of the Soviet Union, believing that commerce and a free flow of ideas with the United States would "kill bolshevism." In 1926 he wrote a letter to the president of the U.S. Chamber of Commerce arguing for recognition of the Soviet Union. Lee's letter eventually made front page headlines. Lee continued through the 1920s to push for United States recognition of the Soviet Union, leading to many false accusations that Lee was in the employ of the Soviet government as a propagandist. Present Day Russia (1928) outlined his observations of the Soviet Union made during a trip in 1927. At the time of Lee's death, he was again embroiled in controversy surrounding his consulting work for I. G. Farben Industries of Germany. Many individuals claimed he was in the employ of the Nazi government. No proof was ever found that this allegation was correct.
Lee married Cornelia Bartlett Bigelow in 1901. The couple had three children: Alice Lee (Cudlipp) in 1902, James Wideman Lee II in 1906, and Ivy Lee, Jr. in 1909. Ivy Lee died of a brain tumor on November 9, 1934; he was 57 years old.
Organizational History of Ivy Lee & Associates
The firm was opened on April 1, 1916 by Ivy Lee. Partners in the firm included W. W. Harris, a newspaper man, and James W. Lee, Jr, Ivy's brother, who had also done publicity work for the Pennsylvania Railroad. The firm was originally known as Lee, Harris and Lee. Later the name was changed to Ivy Lee and Associates. The firm took on many prominent clients, among them the Pennsylvania Railroad, John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and Jr., various investment houses, industrial organizations, and philanthropic institutions. T. J. Ross joined the firm in 1919.
In 1933 the name of the firm was changed to Ivy L. Lee and T. J. Ross. T. J. Ross became a senior partner and the other members of the staff junior partners. The junior partners in 1933 were Burnham Carter, Harcourt Parrish, Joseph Ripley, James W. Lee II, and Ivy L. Lee, Jr. At Ivy Lee's death, T J. Ross became the senior partner. In 1944 Ivy Lee, Jr. withdrew from the firm and opened his own office in San Francisco. In 1961, at James W. Lee II's retirement from the firm, its name was changed to T. J. Ross and Associates, Inc.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of assorted material by and about Lee and his involvement in the history, development and practice of public relations work in the United States during the first half of the twentieth century. The material includes correspondence, writings, and personal material on both Ivy Lee and his immediate family.
In addition, the corporate records of the public relations firm Ivy Lee & Associates are also included in the papers. The records cover the period 1916 through 1946. These records consist of materials used in various public relations campaigns. Some of the larger clients represented are John D. Rockefeller Sr. and Jr., the Pennsylvania Railroad, Armour Inc., Bethlehem Steel and Chrysler Corporation.
Conditions Governing Access
LINKED DIGITAL CONTENT NOTE: Please note that some previously linked digital content is temporarily unavailable while the data is being migrated from an outdated access service. If you would like to access this content, please send a request to Mudd Library.
Collection is open for research use.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers were given to the Princeton University in the late 1950s by the Lee family. Subsequently, public relations material (Matter Sent Out volumes) from Ivy Lee and Associates, was a gift of T. J. Ross and Associates in 1978. Over the last thirty years Ivy Lee's sons and daughter have on occasion donated additional papers to the Library.
Appraisal
No information about appraisal is available for this collection.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital images of the Interborough Rapid Transit Company "Subway Sun" and "Elevated Express" from 1918 to 1932 are available via the Princeton University Library Digital Collections website.
Related Materials
Related Archival Material at Seeley G. Mudd Manuscript Library
Princeton University Scrapbooks
Princeton University Class of 1898
Princeton University Senior Theses on Ivy Lee
Atwater, Edward Sanford, IV, Practice or Principle: A Study of Ivy Lee (1967: History, 124 pp.)
Beckwith, Stephen Ross, Counsellor to Big Business: Ivy Lee and Business Reform, 1900-1930 (1964: Woodrow Wilson School, 143 pp.)
Berlin, Arnold Mark, Ivy Lee (1946: Woodrow Wilson School, 149 pp.)
Halsey, MacDonald Brooke, Ivy Lee and Russia (1966: History, 102 pp.)
Lyon, Peter Baker, Ivy L. Lee: Public Relations Theory and Practice (1968: History, 78 pp.)
Pendray, G. Edward, Papers
McAneny, George C., Papers (material on Interborough Rapid Transit)
Related Archival Material at Other Institutions
The Rockefeller Archives Center, Tarrytown, NY
Harcourt Parrish Papers, University of Virginia
Hagley Museum and Library, Wilmington, DE (Pennsylvania Railroad Collection)
Pennsylvania State Archives, Harrisburg, PA (Pennsylvania Railroad Collection)
Related Publications
Hiebert, Ray Eldon, Courtier to the Crowd: The Story of Ivy Lee and the Development of Public Relations (Ames, Iowa: Iowa State University Press, 1966)
Lee, Ivy Ledbetter, The City for the People: The Best Administration New York Ever Had (New York: Citizens Union, 1903)
Lee, Ivy Ledbetter, Human Nature and Railroads (Philadelphia: E. S. Nash & Co., 1915)
Lee, Ivy Ledbetter, Memories of Uncle Remus: Joel Chandler Harris as Seen and Remembered by a Few of His Friends (New York: privately printed, 1908)
Lee, Ivy Ledbetter, Present-Day Russia (New York: The Macmillan Co., 1928)
Lee, Ivy Ledbetter, U.S.S.R.: A World Enigma (New York: privately printed, 1927)
Advertising -- United States -- 20th century.; Anthracite coal industry -- Public relations.; Fathers and sons -- 20th century -- Correspondence.; Industrial publicity.; Public relations -- United States -- Banks and banking -- 20th century.; Public relations -- United States -- Industry -- 20th century.; Public relations -- United States -- Petroleum industry -- 20th century.; Public relations -- United States -- Railroads -- 20th century.; Public relations -- United States -- 20th century.; Public relations and politics -- United States -- 20th century.; Public relations consultants -- United States -- 20th century -- Records and correspondence.; Railroads -- United States -- Management -- 20th century.; New York (N.Y.) -- Politics and government -- 1898-1951.; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Files.; American history/20th century; Lee, Ivy L. (Ivy Ledbetter), 1877-1934 -- Photographs.; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison), 1839-1937 -- Public opinion.; Kahn, Otto Hermann, 1867-1934.; Lee, James Wideman, 1849-1919.; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison), 1839-1937.; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison), 1874-1960.; Interborough Rapid Transit Company of New York -- Public relations.; National Board of Fire Underwriters -- Public relations.; New York Trust Company -- Public relations.; Pennsylvania Railroad -- Public relations.; Princeton University -- Alumni and alumnae.; Princeton University -- Public relations.; Princeton University -- Students.; Princeton University. Class of 1898.; Socony Mobil Oil Company -- Public relations.; Standard Oil Company -- Public relations.; Western Union Telegraph Company -- Public relations.; T. J. Ross and Associates, Inc.
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1905-1935; 4 boxes
  Conditions Governing Access
  LINKED DIGITAL CONTENT NOTE: Please note that some previously linked digital content is temporarily unavailable while the data is being migrated from an outdated access service. If you would like to access this content, please send a request to Mudd Library.
  Collection is open for research use.
  Scope and Contents
  Ivy Lee corresponded with a wide variety of individuals, but the correspondence series does not reflect the wide range of correspondence which Lee must have carried on with these individuals. Included are presidents of various companies and other well known business and government individuals. Many of the letters acknowledge the exchange of printed matter or routine affairs. Also included are letters received concerning publications of Ivy Lee's. The correspondence with John D. Rockefeller, Jr. is the most complete set, illustrating Lee's and Rockefeller's working relationship from 1914, when Lee was hired by the Rockefeller family, to Lee's death in 1934.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - A, 1923-1925; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Advertising Agency Letters, 1924; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aldrich, Winthrop (Chase National Bank), 1932-1933; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Allen, Ethan, 1912; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Railway Problem, 1910; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Tobacco Company, 1928-1934; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Amtorg Trading Company, 1927-1932; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Armour and Company (Packers Consent Decree), 1932; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish, 1934; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Atterbury, W. W. (Pennsylvania Railroad), 1912-1934; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - B, 1927-1934; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Baker, George Barr, 1926-1933; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Baker, Newton, 1931; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bankers Trust Company (Polish Loan), 1927-1928; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Barbour, W. Warren, 1934; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bell, James F, 1931; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bickel, Carl (United Press), 1927-1932; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Blair and Company (Rumanian Loan), 1928; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Boomer, Lucias (Waldorf-Astoria), 1930-1932; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Boynton, C. H, 1927-1932; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Brisbane, Arthur, 1923-1933; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bruno, Harry, 1923; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - C, 1925-1934; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Cassel, Gustav, Memorandum concerning, 1923 August; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Chadbourne, Thomas L, 1931-1932; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Chrysler, Walter P. (Chrysler Inc.), 1931-1932; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Clement, M. W, 1932-1933; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Cooper, Kent, 1925-1932; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - County, A. J, 1923-1933; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - D, 1927-1934; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Davidson, Jo, 1928-1929; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Davison, Henry P. (American Red Cross), 1918; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Dennett, Tyler, 1930; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Dickerman, William C, 1926-1931; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Dixon, G. D, 1912; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Dodds, Harold Willis, 1933-1934; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Dominick, Goerge G, 1929-1930; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Dulles, John Foster, 1926; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Dunham, Robert J, 1932-1933; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - E, 1923-1930; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Eastern Presidents Conference, 1924-1935; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Easton, Roswell F, 1921-1923; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Electric Railway Journal, 1916-1918; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Ewing, Frederic (Standard Oil), 1932; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - F, 1925-1934; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Filsinger, E. B, 1926; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fischer, Louis, 1930-1932; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Forrestal, James V, 1928-1929; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - G, 1927-1934; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Gates, Artemus L, 1931-1932; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Gibbons, Herbert Adams, 1929; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Gibson, Harvey D, 1928-1932; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Grace, Eugene, 1928-1934; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Gruneberger, Alfred, 1923-1926; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Guggenheim, Harry and Daniel Guggenheim Fund, 1923-1932; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - H, 1926-1934; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Hahn, Paul (American Tobacco Company), 1932; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Harris, Winthrop and Company, 1909-1912; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Hibben, John Grier, 1925; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Hill, George W. (American Tobacco Company), 1928-1934; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Hines, Walker D, 1928-1931; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1931; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - "Human Nature and the Railroads", 1915; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Hutchinson, B. E. (Chrysler Corporation), 1930-1934; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - I-K, 1930-1932; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Inquiry to Bankers concerning Interest Rates, 1930 February; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Jones, Gareth, 1932-1934; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Kahn, Otto, 1918; 1931; 1933; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Kellog, Frank B. (Secretary of State), 1927; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Kennedy, M. C, 1912; 1927-1934; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Kingsley, Darwin, 1926-1934; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - L, 1925-1934; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Lamont, Thomas W, 1930-1931; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - LeBoutillier, George, 1932-1933; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Lebrot, William H, 1932; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Lee, Elisha (Pennsylvania Railroad), 1920; 1927; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Lee, James Melvin, 1925-1928; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Lee, James W. Jr, 1918; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Lee, T. G. (Armour and Company), 1927; 1932-1934; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Lichtenstein, Walter, 1933; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - London School of Economics, 1912; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - M, 1926-1934; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Mann, Sir John, 1927; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - McCulloh, James, 1931-1932; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Mills, E. S. (ASCAP), 1932-1934; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Morrow, Dwight, 1923; 1927; 1930; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Murname, George, 1928; 1931-1933; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Grayson, M. P. Murphy, 1918; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - N-O, 1925-1934; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Olds, Richard Edwin (Assistant Secretary of State), 1926; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - P-R, 1923-1934; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Parrish, Harcourt, 1932; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Patton, W.A., 1909-1912; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Peck, G. L, 1911-1912; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Pennsylvania Railroad, 1909-1912; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Pierson, Lewis E, 1927; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Powell, Francis E, 1912; 1927-1934; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Powell, W. H, 1923; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Prime Minister of Great Britain Speaks on Anglo-American Relations Memorandum, 1929; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - "Publicity Some of the Things it is and is Not", 1925; 1 box
    - A-D, 1925; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - E-H, 1925; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 16)
      [I-Z missing]
  - Purviance, J. N, 1909-1910; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Quinn, Charles J, 1932; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - The Railroad Situation Memorandum, 1932; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Reed, Philip (Armour & Company), 1931-1932; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Roberts, George S, 1930; 1932; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Rockefeller, John D. Jr. and concerning Rockefeller interests, 1914-1935; 2 folders (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
  - Rockefeller advisory staff appointment, 1914-1915; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Royal Institute of International Affairs, 1934; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Russia A World Enigma", 1927; 1 box
    - A-J, 1927; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - K-Z, 1927; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Russian Department of the Treasury, questions addressed to, 1905; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Ryan, John D. (Anaconda Copper Mining), 1924; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - S, 1927-1934; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Scheffer, Paul, 1928; 1931-1932; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Schiff, Mortimer L, 1923; 1930; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Schley, Reeve, 1927; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Schwab, Charles M, 1931; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Scott, S. C, 1910-1912; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Sloan, Alfred P, 1932; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Sloan, George A, 1930; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Speyer & Company (Bulgarian Loan), 1923; 1928; 1930; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Stamp, Josiah, 1928-1934; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Strauss, Percy (Macy and Company), 1933-1934; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Strawn, Silas H, 1932; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Sugar Interests, 1922; 1931-1933; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - T-V, 1928-1934; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Tatnall, Henry, 1911-1912; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Thayer, J. B, 1907-1912; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Thirkeild, Wilbur, 1928; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Thornton, Henry W, 1930; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Traylor, Melvin A. (First National Bank), 1932; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - W-Z, 1925-1934; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Wells, Philip B, 1931; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - White, F. Edison (Armour & Company), 1924; 1929-1931; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Whitney, Richard, 1932; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Wiggin, Albert (United Hospital Fund), undated; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Winkler, Max, 1929; 1931; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Young, Owen D, 1926-1932; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - outgoing unidentified, 1925-1934; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Series 2: International Affairs, 1923-1934; 2 boxes
  This series consists of various forms of material documenting Ivy Lee's interest in matters relating to Europe. Much of Lee's effort in the international arena concerned financial matters, stemming from his work for Harris, Winthrop and Company. The researcher interested in international affairs will also want to look at Lee's writings, speeches, memorandum, and the publication Information from Ivy Lee & Associates.
  The materials include an interview with President Calvin Coolidge on war debts and reparations, especially as they concern the Mellon-Beranger agreement (1927) on the elimination of Inter-Allied war debts. Lee believed that compelling full European payment of debts would undermine the economy of both the United States and Europe because of the resulting loss of trade. The Interviews and Reports by Dr. Gibbons describe European sentiment on the Mellon-Beranger agreement. The John Maynard Keynes Memorandum was a confidential memorandum written by Keynes to the British Prime Minister offering information and insight on the United States economic situation in 1931. Lee sent the confidential memorandum to many of his friends and business connections.